<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<!--
		CDATA tags mean no need to escape special characters.
		Don't worry about spaces at the start/end. That gets trimmed.
	-->


	<!-- The title of this mod. -->
	<title><![CDATA[ Instant Clone and Heal after Battle ]]></title>


	<!--
		This mod's thread on subsetgames.com.
		If there's no thread yet, create one to announce your upcoming mod in the
		forum. Then paste the url here.
	-->
	<threadUrl><![CDATA[ https://ftlmultiverse.boards.net/thread/48/instant-clone-heal-after-battle ]]></threadUrl>


	<!-- Your forum user name. -->
	<author><![CDATA[ Choosechee ]]></author>


	<!--
		The revision/variant of this release, preferably at least a number.
		Examples:
			0.3
			2.1c Ships Only WIP
			2.4.1 Hi-res Bkgs
			1.0 for FTL 1.03.1
	-->
	<version><![CDATA[ 2.0 ]]></version>


	<description>
<![CDATA[
This addon makes it so that in safe environments, cloning is instant and your crew are automatically healed if there is an available source of free healing. The environment is considered safe if you can upgrade your systems, there are no fires on your ship, your oxygen system, if it exists, isn't broken and you have at least 70% oxygen, and, specifically for the healing part, there are no breached systems. For healing, individual crew member must also be safe, i.e, not taking damage from suffocation or other sources, though this is handled on a per-crew basis and will not prevent safe crew from being healed. Valid sources of healing are a powered medbay, a crew member with healing abilities, a self-healing crew member (only counting for themselves, of course), or other sources that are currently healing the crew. Due to Hyperspace limitations, augments with healing effects will not count for instant healing unless they are currently healing the crew.

This mod is meant to be purely quality of life, and not make the game easier. If you find a situation where this mod gives you an advantage, please tell me so I can fix it. If you are a mod developer and you have modded crew that count for healing when they shouldn't, put their crew ID or power definition in the mods.ichb.crewHealBlackList and/or mods.ihcb.selfHealBlackList in Lua. Do not use table.insert, instead do blackList[crewIdOrPowerDef] = true. This will provide a bandaid fix while I look at the root problem.
]]>
	</description>

	<!--
		Suggestions for the description...

		Write a short paragraph about the mod's effect first (what style ship, how
		does it affect gameplay). No need to introduce yourself.

		Optionally add a paragraph of background flavor.

		Optionally list important features.

		List any concerns about mod compatibility, preferred order, or requirements.

		Mention "Replaces the XYZ ship." if relevant.
			Kestrel-A, Engi-A,    Fed-A,     Zoltan-A,
			Stealth-A, Rock-A,    Slug-A,    Mantis-A,
			Lanius-A,  Crystal-A

		Above all, keep the description general, so you won't have to edit
		that again for each new version.
	-->
</metadata>
