<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<title><![CDATA[ More Mannable Systems ]]></title>
	<threadUrl><![CDATA[ https://ftlmultiverse.boards.net/thread/73 ]]></threadUrl>
	<author><![CDATA[ kokoro11 ]]></author>
	<version><![CDATA[ 2.0 ]]></version>
	<description>
<![CDATA[
More Mannable Systems 2.0 is here, introducing crew manning skill level progression!

This addon expands your strategic options by allowing crew members to man a wider array of ship systems beyond the standard six systems. Granting direct control over more systems provides unique tactical advantages and enhances your ship's capabilities.

New Feature: Manning Skill Levels
This feature requires the "ADVANCED MANNING" option to be enabled.
Crew members can now gain experience and level up their proficiency at manning the newly available systems. A crew member's skill level determines the power of the bonus they provide.
How to Gain Skill: Crew gain experience simply by manning a system or by being at the station when the system is used during combat.
Training Limit: A single crew member can only gain up to 2 skill points for the same system per jump.
Exclusions: Crew Drones cannot gain skills.

Manning Bonuses:
Bonuses now scale with your crew's manning skills*.
- Oxygen: Increases oxygen refill speed by 100/200/300%.
- Drones: Increases drone operating speed by 20/30/40% (both crew and space drones).
- Artillery: Boosts weapon recharge speed by 10/20/30%.
- Temporal*: Reduces system cooldown by 20/33/43%.
- Cloaking*: Increases evasion by 40% while cloaking is active.
  + (Level 1) Also reduces system cooldown by 20%.
  + (Level 2) Also increases evasion by 10% while system is powered.
- Mind Control*: Extends mind control duration by 25%.
  + (Level 1) Also reduces system cooldown by 50%.
  + (Level 2) Also causes the mind controlled crew to act twice as fast.
- Hacking*: Accelerates hacking speed by 25%.
  + (Level 1) Also reduces system cooldown by 20%.
  + (Level 2) Also counters enemy's hacking drone.

*ADVANCED MANNING Game Option:
To access the new features, you must enable the "ADVANCED MANNING" option in the main menu. This option unlocks:
- The ability to man the Cloaking, Mind Control, Hacking, and Temporal systems.
- The entire Manning Skill Level progression and its associated tiered bonuses.

Compatibility:
More Mannable Systems is designed for broad compatibility with other Multiverse addons. For a detailed list of compatible addons, please see the dedicated "Compatibility List" Below.

Crucial Installation Note: For seamless functionality, ensure More Mannable Systems is patched LAST after all other addons!

Recommended Patch Order:

1. MV Assets
2. MV Data
3. ... (Other Addons) ...
4. More Mannable Systems


Latest Version: v2.0
Download Link: https://github.com/kokoro11/more_mannable/releases


Changelog:
v2.0:
- New feature: manning skill levels.
- Updated compatibility with other addons.
v1.5:
- Updated for compatibility with Multiverse 5.5.
- Fixed an oxygen overflow bug.
v1.3:
- Updated for compatibility with Federation Special Forces v1.1.
v1.2:
- Updated for compatibility with Forgemaster v0.6 and Forgotten Races v13.0.

Compatibility List:

THE RENEGADE COLLECTION
FORGOTTEN RACES
FORGOTTEN RACES - DIAMOND
The Outer Expansion
R&D
Fishier Than Light
Galaxy On Fire
Darkest Desire
Insurrection+ Selection (IPS)
Cosmic Metalloid Expansion
The Tardis
FTLLJAMMER
The Potential - Multiverse Edition
FTL: FORGEMASTER
Tradition N Experiment
Obsidian Cruiser
Escort Duty
Tiberian Sun Pack
Tantive IV
AI Cruisers
HEKTAR COLLECTION
Dino's Hangar
Faster Than Cobalt
Lizzard's Variety
Federation Special Forces
]]>
	</description>
</metadata>
