<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<title><![CDATA[ Universal Weapon Modularity ]]></title>
	<threadUrl><![CDATA[ https://github.com/kokoro11/modular_weapons ]]></threadUrl>
	<author><![CDATA[ kokoro11 ]]></author>
	<version><![CDATA[ 0.1 ]]></version>
	<description>
<![CDATA[
Ever wished you could slap a Hullbust Module on your trusty Burst Laser II? Or give a Pike Beam the shield-piercing power it deserves? Now you can.

Universal Weapon Modularity(UWM) breaks the chains of Hektar's proprietary technology, allowing you to install their powerful weapon modules on any weapon in your arsenal, not just the designated "modular" ones.

This mod fundamentally changes how you approach your ship's loadout, opening up a universe of new strategic possibilities. Turn any weapon into the perfect tool for the job.

Latest Version: v0.1
Download Link: https://github.com/kokoro11/modular_weapons/releases

Cost to install a module on a non-modular weapon: 30 scrap, 3 fuel, 3 missiles, 3 drone parts.
Note: The resources used for installation will not be refunded when you detach the module or sell the weapon. Choose your modifications wisely!

Module Effects:
Each weapon can accept one Attribute Module and one Status Module.

Standard Modules:
RAD Module: +30 crew damage
Cooldown Module: -20% weapon charge time
Lockdown Module: Applies lockdown effect to the target room
Pierce Module: +1 shield pierce, +30% breach chance
Neural Module: +100% stun chance, +10s stun duration
Accuracy Module: +20% accuracy. For beams, this is replaced with +1 shield pierce
Firestarter Module: +30% fire chance
Hullbust Module: 2x damage vs. systemless rooms, +30% breach chance
Power Module: +1 power cost, -20% weapon charge speed, +1 damage per shot

Advanced Modules (Requires The Hektar Expansion mod by @RoadTrain):
Charge Module: Reduces a weapon to a single shot but significantly cuts its charge time. The new charge time is the original charge time divided by twice the original number of shots (e.g., A 4-shot weapon becomes a 1-shot weapon with 1/8th the charge time). Incompatible with beam and single-shot weapons.
Adaptive Module: +1 power cost, -20% weapon charge speed. Each time this weapon fires, its damage permanently increases by 1 for the rest of the combat. This effect stacks up to 3 times.
Chain Module: Each time this weapon fires, its charge time is reduced by 10%. This effect stacks up to 3 times for a total of -30% charge time.
]]>
	</description>
</metadata>